<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>docker - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</title><link>maki.bzh/tags/docker/</link><description>docker - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 21:57:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="maki.bzh/tags/docker/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Gs move in silence like lasagna</title><link>maki.bzh/realgsmoveinsilencelikelasagna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/realgsmoveinsilencelikelasagna/</guid><description>In this article, I will introduce you to Odie&amp;rsquo;s misfortunes. Odie is a final year student at ENSIBS Cyberdefense (France). He is also the biggest fan of the famous band: Iron Maiden. In addition to that, he built a small fan website for them on his Virtual Private Server. Given that, Odie is a poor student, he only owns one VPS for his tests, courses and others stuff. But, Odie comes from the most prestigious school in cyberdefense, then he knows how to protect himself against awful hackers&amp;hellip; Well, almost.</description></item><item><title>[Santhacklaus 2019] - Naughty Docker</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/santhacklaus2019naughtydockre/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/santhacklaus2019naughtydockre/</guid><description><![CDATA[It looks like a naughty developer has been deploying a Docker image on a Santa production server a few days before Christmas. He was in a rush and was not able to properly pass all security checks on the built Docker image. Would be a shame if this image could give you an SSH access to the production server&hellip; http://46.30.204.47&quot;
Etat des lieux En allant sur l&rsquo;IP donnée dans l&rsquo;énoncé, on trouve une note nous donnait accès au docker en question.]]></description></item><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Microservices</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</guid><description>0_Intrusion Welcome to MicroServices inc, where do all things micro and service oriented! Recently we got an alert saying there was suspicious traffic on one of our web servers. Can you help us out?
Filename MD5 hash Download link microservice.pcap 18d2c48f5d03d5faa5cb4473f9819b4b https://mega.nz/#!Gv5zAahB!afQTRfSLEE93xDDoZbi0EoGLrGzshAALLCS-1LwykdY What is the IP Address of the attacker? For this flag I don&amp;rsquo;t have any real analysis, I just opened the PCAP file and looked at the different TCP conversations.</description></item></channel></rss>