<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>cryptography - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</title><link>maki.bzh/tags/cryptography/</link><description>cryptography - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 21:57:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="maki.bzh/tags/cryptography/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[French FCSC] - Chapardeur de mots de passe</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/fcscfrench2020chapardeur/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/fcscfrench2020chapardeur/</guid><description><![CDATA[Un ami vous demande de l&rsquo;aide pour déterminer si l&rsquo;email qu&rsquo;il vient d&rsquo;ouvrir au sujet du Covid-19 était malveillant et si c&rsquo;était le cas, ce qu&rsquo;il risque. Il prétend avoir essayé d&rsquo;ouvrir le fichier joint à cet mail sans y parvenir. Peu de temps après, une fenêtre liée à l&rsquo;anti-virus a indiqué, entre autre, le mot KPOT v2.0 mais rien d&rsquo;apparent n&rsquo;est arrivé en dehors de cela.
Après une analyse préliminaire, votre ami vous informe qu&rsquo;il est probable que ce malware ait été légèrement modifié, étant donné que le contenu potentiellement exfiltré (des parties du format de texte et de fichier avant chiffrement) ne semble plus prédictible.]]></description></item><item><title>[FIC 2020] - Hexpresso CTF Prequals</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/hexpressofix2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/hexpressofix2020/</guid><description><![CDATA[Le CTF &ldquo;CaptureTheFic&rdquo; est organisé par l&rsquo;équipe de CTF &ldquo;Hexpresso&rdquo;. Equipe connue pour ses différents résultats en CTF et pour l&rsquo;organisation de CTF, tel que le BreizhCTF.
CaptureTheFic se déroule en deux étapes:
Une étape de pré-qualifications en ligne avec énormément d&rsquo;équipes; Une phase finale au FIC, composée des 14 meilleures équipes issues des pré-qualifications. Comme ce writeup le montrera, ce CTF n&rsquo;est pas un jeopardy standard. Cette préqualification comporte 8 étapes et il est nécessaire de terminer une épreuve pour accéder à la suivante.]]></description></item><item><title>[Santhacklaus 2019] - Jacques ! Au secours !</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/santhacklaus2019jacquiesheerhask/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/santhacklaus2019jacquiesheerhask/</guid><description>One of our VIP clients, who wishes to remain anonymous, has apparently been hacked and all their important documents are now corrupted. Can you help us recover the files? We found a strange piece of software that might have caused all of this. MD5 of the file : ccaab91b06fc9a77f3b98d2b9164df8e Fichiers: http://cloud.id-iot.team/s/e2ZgLdHKwMoFQ8x
Etat des lieux Cette épreuve commence donc avec une archive zip contenant plusieurs fichiers:
Le fichier &amp;ldquo;READ_THIS.txt&amp;rdquo; contient un message charmant:</description></item><item><title>[Santhacklaus 2019] - Revmomon</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/santhacklaus2019revmomon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/santhacklaus2019revmomon/</guid><description><![CDATA[Suspicious activity has been detected. Probably nothing to be scared about but take a look anyway. If you find anything, a backdoor, a malware or anything of this kind, flag is the sha256 of it. MD5 of the file : c93adc996da5dda82312e43e9a91d053 PCAP : https://mega.nz/#!eqQV3SwD!_jAfHMqMw9d-LIDoTDR9JziwNicsxkYymS87eR4pLUg
Etat des lieux A l&rsquo;ouverture du PCAP, on peut voir énormément de paquets entre l&rsquo;ip 172.17.0.5 et 172.17.0.1. Du premier paquet au 170281, c&rsquo;est une alternance de paquets SYN / RST, caractéristique d&rsquo;un Stealth Scan de nmap.]]></description></item><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Microservices</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</guid><description>0_Intrusion Welcome to MicroServices inc, where do all things micro and service oriented! Recently we got an alert saying there was suspicious traffic on one of our web servers. Can you help us out?
Filename MD5 hash Download link microservice.pcap 18d2c48f5d03d5faa5cb4473f9819b4b https://mega.nz/#!Gv5zAahB!afQTRfSLEE93xDDoZbi0EoGLrGzshAALLCS-1LwykdY What is the IP Address of the attacker? For this flag I don&amp;rsquo;t have any real analysis, I just opened the PCAP file and looked at the different TCP conversations.</description></item><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Reading rainbow</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019readingrainbow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019readingrainbow/</guid><description>Recently, the office put up a private webserver to store important information about the newest research project for the company. This information was to be kept confidential, as it&amp;rsquo;s release could mean a large loss for everyone in the office. Just as the research was about to be published, a competing firm published information eerily similar. Too similar&amp;hellip; Time to take a look through the office network logs to figure out what happened.</description></item><item><title>[OtterCTF] - Network</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/otterctf2018network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/otterctf2018network/</guid><description>Network There are 4 network challenges during this CTF, I only solved 3 of them, here is how.
Birdman&amp;rsquo;s Data State of the art The PCAP file is not really big, I decided to open it using Wireshark. There are few things to notice:
Data in UDP protocol HTTP packets to txtwizard.net There nothing interesting in UDP traffic, data does not represent much.
On the other hand, HTTP traffic is very interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>