<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>wireshark - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</title><link>maki.bzh/tags/wireshark/</link><description>wireshark - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 21:57:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="maki.bzh/tags/wireshark/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[ECSC] - Exfiltration</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/ecscfrench2019exfiltration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/ecscfrench2019exfiltration/</guid><description><![CDATA[Description Notre SoC a détecté qu&rsquo;un document confidentiel avait été exfiltré ! La méthode utilisée ne semble pas avancée et heureusement, une capture réseau a pu être faite au bon moment&hellip; Retrouvez ce document.
Trouver la configuration de l&rsquo;extraction On commence cette épreuve par une capture réseau. Comme à chaque fois en matière d&rsquo;exfiltration, il suffit de trouver un bout du filon pour le remonter complètement.
Fig 6: Configuration de l&rsquo;exfiltration]]></description></item><item><title>[ECSC] - Petites notes</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/ecscfrench2019petitenote/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/ecscfrench2019petitenote/</guid><description>Description Connaissez-vous bien le format PCAPng ?
Etat des lieux On commence donc ce challenge avec une capture réseau. Premier réflexe de CTF avec un format de flag : strings.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 ➜ petitenote hexdump -C petites_notes.pcapng | grep -C 10 &amp;#39;ECSC&amp;#39; 001b3f80 00 0a 00 00 2f 03 6e 73 31 05 6b 61 73 65 63 02 |.</description></item><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Microservices</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</guid><description>0_Intrusion Welcome to MicroServices inc, where do all things micro and service oriented! Recently we got an alert saying there was suspicious traffic on one of our web servers. Can you help us out?
Filename MD5 hash Download link microservice.pcap 18d2c48f5d03d5faa5cb4473f9819b4b https://mega.nz/#!Gv5zAahB!afQTRfSLEE93xDDoZbi0EoGLrGzshAALLCS-1LwykdY What is the IP Address of the attacker? For this flag I don&amp;rsquo;t have any real analysis, I just opened the PCAP file and looked at the different TCP conversations.</description></item><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Reading rainbow</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019readingrainbow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019readingrainbow/</guid><description>Recently, the office put up a private webserver to store important information about the newest research project for the company. This information was to be kept confidential, as it&amp;rsquo;s release could mean a large loss for everyone in the office. Just as the research was about to be published, a competing firm published information eerily similar. Too similar&amp;hellip; Time to take a look through the office network logs to figure out what happened.</description></item><item><title>PCAP analysis : How to basic</title><link>maki.bzh/shorts/wiresharkhowtobasics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/shorts/wiresharkhowtobasics/</guid><description>Introduction Whether in &amp;ldquo;Capture The Flag&amp;rdquo; (CTF) events or even in professional life, we work with network captures. PCAP (Packet capture), is rich in information. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get lost in the amount of information and start on wrong tracks. Throughout this MOOC, I will introduce you the methodology to be adopted to deal with this type of situation. Firstly, I will try to describe the PCAP content, list some tools and finally practical exercises resulting from CTF tests or malicious traffic.</description></item><item><title>[OtterCTF] - Network</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/otterctf2018network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/otterctf2018network/</guid><description>Network There are 4 network challenges during this CTF, I only solved 3 of them, here is how.
Birdman&amp;rsquo;s Data State of the art The PCAP file is not really big, I decided to open it using Wireshark. There are few things to notice:
Data in UDP protocol HTTP packets to txtwizard.net There nothing interesting in UDP traffic, data does not represent much.
On the other hand, HTTP traffic is very interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>