<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>tamuctf - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</title><link>maki.bzh/tags/tamuctf/</link><description>tamuctf - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="maki.bzh/tags/tamuctf/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Honeypots</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019honeypots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019honeypots/</guid><description>This part of the writeup will go pretty fast, it&amp;rsquo;s just parsing in the end. All challenges are in the following archive:
Password for the archive: tamuctf
Filename MD5 Hash Download link honeypot2.7z b08992d50e5885f6db8cf50f22eefab4 https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1lhYsk97AgYDMxzfz1r6FzUs28sugZUR0&amp;export=download Warning this challenge contains some malware samples.
Cowrie What was the most common src ip (telnet &amp;amp; ssh)? What was the most common telnet username? What was the most common ssh username? What is the url and channel of the IRC server that the one downloaded script tried to connect to?</description></item><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Microservices</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019microservices/</guid><description>0_Intrusion Welcome to MicroServices inc, where do all things micro and service oriented! Recently we got an alert saying there was suspicious traffic on one of our web servers. Can you help us out?
Filename MD5 hash Download link microservice.pcap 18d2c48f5d03d5faa5cb4473f9819b4b https://mega.nz/#!Gv5zAahB!afQTRfSLEE93xDDoZbi0EoGLrGzshAALLCS-1LwykdY What is the IP Address of the attacker? For this flag I don&amp;rsquo;t have any real analysis, I just opened the PCAP file and looked at the different TCP conversations.</description></item><item><title>[TamuCTF 2019] - Reading rainbow</title><link>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019readingrainbow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/writeups/tamu2019readingrainbow/</guid><description>Recently, the office put up a private webserver to store important information about the newest research project for the company. This information was to be kept confidential, as it&amp;rsquo;s release could mean a large loss for everyone in the office. Just as the research was about to be published, a competing firm published information eerily similar. Too similar&amp;hellip; Time to take a look through the office network logs to figure out what happened.</description></item></channel></rss>