<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>blue team - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</title><link>maki.bzh/tags/blue-team/</link><description>blue team - Tag - Maki's adventure | Internet of things, IoT, ICS, forensic, pentest, red team &amp; more :)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 21:57:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="maki.bzh/tags/blue-team/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Gs move in silence like lasagna</title><link>maki.bzh/realgsmoveinsilencelikelasagna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/realgsmoveinsilencelikelasagna/</guid><description>In this article, I will introduce you to Odie&amp;rsquo;s misfortunes. Odie is a final year student at ENSIBS Cyberdefense (France). He is also the biggest fan of the famous band: Iron Maiden. In addition to that, he built a small fan website for them on his Virtual Private Server. Given that, Odie is a poor student, he only owns one VPS for his tests, courses and others stuff. But, Odie comes from the most prestigious school in cyberdefense, then he knows how to protect himself against awful hackers&amp;hellip; Well, almost.</description></item><item><title>PCAP analysis : How to basic</title><link>maki.bzh/shorts/wiresharkhowtobasics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><author>Maki</author><guid>maki.bzh/shorts/wiresharkhowtobasics/</guid><description>Introduction Whether in &amp;ldquo;Capture The Flag&amp;rdquo; (CTF) events or even in professional life, we work with network captures. PCAP (Packet capture), is rich in information. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get lost in the amount of information and start on wrong tracks. Throughout this MOOC, I will introduce you the methodology to be adopted to deal with this type of situation. Firstly, I will try to describe the PCAP content, list some tools and finally practical exercises resulting from CTF tests or malicious traffic.</description></item></channel></rss>